<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Michael Lancaster</title>
		<description>Front End Developer/HTML5 Soldier</description>
		<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com/</link>
		
			<item>
				<title>Secrets of Lea Verou about CSS.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not sure when it was but in the end of 2011 or beginning of 2012 I saw &lt;a title='Lea Verou' target='_blank' href='http://lea.verou.me/'&gt;Lea Verou&lt;/a&gt; talking about &amp;#8220;CSS3 Secrets: 10 things you might not know about CSS3&amp;#8221; and it was great see how many great techniques we can use to achieve our &lt;br /&gt; client - side goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='10_things_you_might_not_know_about_css3'&gt;10 things you might not know about CSS3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;object width='640' height='360'&gt;&lt;param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/54wJkqG8jXE?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /&gt;&lt;embed width='640' allowscriptaccess='always' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' height='360' allowfullscreen='true' src='http://www.youtube.com/v/54wJkqG8jXE?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this year (2013) she had another great speak at W3Conf in San Francisco about &amp;#8220;More CSS Secrets: Another 10 things you may not know about CSS&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='more_css_secrets_another_10_things_you_may_not_know_about_css'&gt;More CSS Secrets: Another 10 things you may not know about CSS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;object width='640' height='360'&gt;&lt;param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/3ikye7Qc7Ak?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /&gt;&lt;embed width='640' allowscriptaccess='always' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' height='360' allowfullscreen='true' src='http://www.youtube.com/v/3ikye7Qc7Ak?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see she is a Client - Side hacker specifically in CSS and always bringing new ideas and techniques to solve common problems we used to solve with complex javascript code and hacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>Sun Mar 03 00:00:00 -0600 2013</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/secrets-of-lea-verou-css</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Inspirational Art and Code by Joshua Davis.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine shared this great talk by Joshua Davis at W3Conf in San Francisco. &lt;br /&gt; Joshua&amp;#8217;s work is very inspirational and see these awesome things makes my life better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t forget to check out his website &lt;a title='Joshua Davis' target='_blank' href='http://www.joshuadavis.com/'&gt;Joshua Davis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width='640' height='360'&gt;&lt;param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/LJS4fBjdPM4?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /&gt;&lt;embed width='640' allowscriptaccess='always' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' height='360' allowfullscreen='true' src='http://www.youtube.com/v/LJS4fBjdPM4?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;</description>
				<published>Thu Feb 28 00:00:00 -0600 2013</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/inspirational-art-and-code-by-joshua-davis</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The filter bubble and your social life online.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;At the same time Internet give us liberty to think and see different points about our world in culture, politics, nature, life in general the internet is made by &amp;#8220;man&amp;#8221; and we have our own perspective of the world. Therefore we are doing the same exactly mistakes we are doing offline it&amp;#8217;s just another digital space 1 and 0&amp;#8217;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s sort of funny sometimes how we push things turning every person the &amp;#8220;product of the environment&amp;#8221; even on digital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll never deny that technology in particular internet changed the world for better but I still think we could do much better when we start to change our mindset as a &amp;#8220;person&amp;#8221; for the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching this great video we can see that people don&amp;#8217;t loose their old habits to live in their &amp;#8220;boxes&amp;#8221; and continue to create their &amp;#8220;Extended Mind&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='are_we_going_backwards'&gt;Are we going backwards?!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;object width='640' height='360'&gt;&lt;param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/B8ofWFx525s?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /&gt;&lt;embed width='640' allowscriptaccess='always' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' height='360' allowfullscreen='true' src='http://www.youtube.com/v/B8ofWFx525s?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US' /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;h2 id='i_also_suggest'&gt;I also suggest..&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you to watch this incredible documentary called &lt;a title='internet rising' target='_blanc' href='http://internetrising.net/'&gt;&quot;Internet Rising&quot;&lt;/a&gt; investigating the evolving relationships between the Internet and collective consciousness of humanity. It provokes many questions about ancient and modern paradoxes of life. You definitely should check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width='640' height='360'&gt;&lt;param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/pMh8oBdKkK4?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /&gt;&lt;embed width='640' allowscriptaccess='always' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' height='360' allowfullscreen='true' src='http://www.youtube.com/v/pMh8oBdKkK4?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US' /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both videos are great to inspired us to think about almost everything surround us in the digital life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>Wed Feb 27 00:00:00 -0600 2013</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/the-filter-bubble-and-your-social-life-online</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Let's talk about rem units.</title>
				<description>&lt;h2 id='the_pastpresent'&gt;The past/present&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could talk a lot about all the principal units we have been using but let&amp;#8217;s get this straight we have been using &amp;#8220;px&amp;#8221; since ever and this approach just doesn&amp;#8217;t work anymore or scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code data-language='css'&gt;
.parent {
	font-size: 16px;
}

.child {
	font-size: 12px;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now with the popularity and acceptance of the Responsive Design (web applications accessible in any devices) developers and designers are thinking more about scale things and make it fit to their user&amp;#8217;s device. Style sheets that use relative units can more easily scale from one device environment to another. Therefore we started to scale the font-size transforming pixel in em&amp;#8217;s using this math child / parent = em&amp;#8217;s voila!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code data-language='css'&gt;
.parent {
	font-size: 16px;
}

.child {
	font-size: 0.75em; /* 12 / 16 = 0.75 */
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh! wait. Do we have to repeat this math going through element parent by element parent to give their child the right em&amp;#8217;s values? It&amp;#8217;s hard to believe but yes we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when your wife, girlfriend, dog (whatever) asked you why you are loosing hair and getting bald that&amp;#8217;s your answer &amp;#8220;I use px to calculate em&amp;#8217;s Baby!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='the_presentfuture'&gt;The present/future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now (a while ago) the &lt;a title='W3C spec' target='_blank' href='http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-values/#font-relative-lengths'&gt;W3C spec&lt;/a&gt; added to CSS3 the rem unit that is relative to the document parent (root em).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code data-language='css'&gt;
html {
	font-size: 62.5%;
}

parent {
	font-size: 1.6rem; /* 16px */
}

child {
	font-size: 1.2rem; /* 12px */
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No need to go through all your parent doing that math to change their child and the browser support makes us even happier developers &lt;a title='Can I use rem units?' target='_blank' href='http://caniuse.com/rem'&gt;caniuse.com/rem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='browser_support'&gt;Browser support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IE 9+&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Firefox 3.6+&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Chrome 6+&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Safari 5+&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Opera 11.6+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='old_browser_support'&gt;Old browser support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code data-language='css'&gt;
html {
	font-size: 62.5%;
}

parent {
	font-size: 16px;
	font-size: 1.6rem; /* 16px */
}

child {
	font-size: 12px;
	font-size: 1.2rem; /* 12px */
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s go now change all our style sheets and make it good for all users and developers!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>Tue Feb 26 00:00:00 -0600 2013</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/lets-talk-about-rem-units</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Two years ago everything started.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;While I cook my pasta I do this post so I&amp;#8217;ll be short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my first job I did a test and got my first paid job as a Front End Developer Jr It was hard because we had so many projects and things to do that I wasn&amp;#8217;t used to (Mostly developers used to get there around 9:30 am and leave around 9:30 pm) I used to get home at 1:00 am so I had time to eat fast, shower and get some rest to another day. I had my senior developer supporting and protecting me like a father and I could learn a lot from him not just technical stuff but how to act in certain situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 5 months of my hard core work and a lot of growth this same senior developer indicated me to another company DBR.ag to work as a consultant for some months in a big ongoing project at Chamber of Electric Energy Commercialization in Brazil. Was I and another two developers working hard to delivery the system on time but at that time was more independent and I could be outstanding helping and making improvements to the client side of the system. After 4 months working in-site at CCEE we delivered the system and DBR.ag hired me. At the Agency I started to think in process to help our work flow so I suggested and showed why we we should use Control Version(in that case SVN). I also developed a simple HTML5 markup framework as a good practice to all developers follow and it was very fun. After some months HP called us to come back to CCEE and help the JSP developers with client side mostly with JS/jQuery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest you can guess reading the about me page so let&amp;#8217;s talk about some other topics now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='outdated_developers'&gt;Outdated Developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had great senior developers, but all of them had something in common they were kind of outdated about the new stuff and things we could use maybe because of the hard work flow, family, laziness whatever I just know one of the things that makes difference in a great professional to a good one is his ability to make things better not just getting it done but making it better so I put in my head always look for make it better and stay update to new things that could help improve my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='how_im_doing_it'&gt;How I&amp;#8217;m doing it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m always evaluating myself and looking new ways to improve myself in being a better professional. Lately (around 6 months) I discovered the best way &amp;#8220;for me&amp;#8221; to learn better is read as much as I can about something new that I want to learn before actually try it so I will have like an 360 point of view, a better understanding of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='something_that_i_try_follow_to_keep_me_productive'&gt;Something that I try follow to keep me productive.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class='ui-txt-01'&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Know the shortcuts of your tools and use them wisely.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Choose some sort of &quot;Robot mode playlist&quot; where the songs works just as a background.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Keep focus wake up and think about your tasks for the day that you have to get done.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;First do it, then do it right, then do it better&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Follow the most active and productive guys in your field, stay updated, read, talk, discuss about it when is possible.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Make experiments. Don't have time? make time experiments are very important to expand your view outside of the &quot;work box&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and this work is what keep me awake at night learning new things when everybody else is sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>Mon Feb 25 00:00:00 -0600 2013</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/two-years-ago-everything-started</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What technologies I'm using to blog?!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I needed a new look and as I said in my last (first) post I love to learn and experiment new things and at the same time I&amp;#8217;m not very fan of Wordpress as a developer point of view either. &lt;br /&gt; I agree it is a good CMS/Blog Tool that helps us delivery great products in short time for clients therefore it&amp;#8217;s good for business but Wordpress &amp;#8220;themes&amp;#8221; has a bunch of ugly, messy code and sometimes happens to be infected by other plugins/scripts causing headaches or even worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='long_story_short'&gt;Long story short&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I started looking for something more elegant that I could use git to deploy
So I tried Github Pages and Jekyll a &quot;blog-aware, static site generator in Ruby&quot; that uses Liquid template to process the templates.
But I would do experiments with Node.js and Ruby someday so I choose &lt;a title='Heroku' target='_blank' href='http://www.heroku.com'&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; (cloud application platform for build, deploy, and run cloud apps using Ruby, Node.js, Clojure, Java, Python and Scala).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I Can run and test locally, pretty simple. &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code data-language='ruby'&gt;
foreman start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And After see my changes I want to deploy directly to my cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code data-language='ruby'&gt;
git add .
git commit -m &quot;my message&quot;
git push origin
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done! Beautiful! Everything up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='in_the_backend'&gt;In the Back-End&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heroku Server (AWESOME cloud application platform).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ruby (Jekyll, liquid template).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Git to deploy to my Heroku Cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id='in_the_frontend'&gt;In the Front-End&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML5 (Markup).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;CSS3 (SASS/COMPASS) Modular Development Based.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Responsive Design.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;JS (jQuery).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Markdown (Blogging).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Disqus (comments).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may do a better explanation how it works further on but for now I need some posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>Wed Jan 30 00:00:00 -0600 2013</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/what-technologies-im-using-to-blog</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>First things first.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Since I started to work as a Front End Developer (almost 2 years ago) I&amp;#8217;ve been studying and learning new things every single day and I think now it&amp;#8217;s a good time to start share my humble knowledge and other main reason is that I haven&amp;#8217;t studying English (Yes..shame on me!) just technical/theory stuff instead and Ah I moved from Brazil to US months ago and I want to make my English even better than my Portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So read in English is very common for me but now I need to make my mind think as a native American (I&amp;#8217;m half American by the way but I lived in Brazil for 21 years) explore new words therefore what is the best way to explore this words than practice writing a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Double win here. I will practice my English and keep learning technical stuff :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please be patient and feel free to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>Wed Jan 30 00:00:00 -0600 2013</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/first-things-first</link>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
