<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Michael Lancaster</title>
		<description>Front End Developer/HTML5 Soldier</description>
		<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com/</link>
		
			<item>
				<title>Adding custom parameters to the facebook share</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know why the Facebook documentation for developers miss some very good and basic information. But here&amp;#8217;s what I found to add parameters to the share link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?s=100&amp;amp;p&lt;span&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;=titlehere&amp;amp;p&lt;span&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;=http://www.yoururlhere.com&amp;amp;p&lt;span&gt;summary&lt;/span&gt;=yoursummaryhere&amp;amp;p&lt;span&gt;images&lt;/span&gt;=http://www.urltoyourimage.com&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>Thu Jan 31 00:00:00 -0600 2013</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/adding-parametes-facebook-share</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>First things first</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Since I started to work as a Front End Developer (almost 2 year ago) I&amp;#8217;ve been studying and learning new things every single day and I think now it&amp;#8217;s a good time to start share my humble knowledge and my other main reason is that I haven&amp;#8217;t studying English (Yes..shame on me!) but technical/theory stuff and Ah I moved from Brazil to US months ago and I want to make my English even better than my Portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So read in English is very common for me but now I need to make my mind think as a native American (I&amp;#8217;m half American by the way but I lived in Brazil for 21 year) explore new words therefore what is the best way to explore this words than practice writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I double win here. I will practice my English and keep learning technical stuff :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please be patient and feel free to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>Wed Jan 30 00:00:00 -0600 2013</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/first-things-first</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why I choose use Jekyll instead wordpress</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Vestibulum imperdiet adipiscing arcu, quis aliquam dolor condimentum dapibus. Aliquam fermentum leo aliquet quam volutpat et molestie mauris mattis. Suspendisse semper consequat velit in suscipit. Praesent blandit, mi id facilisis adipiscing, tortor tellus mollis quam, sed dignissim sapien diam ac lectus. Nunc eget ornare quam. Vivamus sit amet tortor dolor, non egestas ligula. Mauris nisi risus, semper nec blandit id, suscipit eget dolor. Sed placerat odio at erat porttitor varius. Phasellus ornare vestibulum dolor ac rhoncus. Mauris laoreet varius est eu rhoncus. Curabitur facilisis mauris eu purus pharetra vitae tincidunt nulla gravida. Duis sagittis, felis a luctus mattis, metus sem tempus velit, sit amet blandit tellus nisi id augue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proin feugiat libero ac lorem mollis fermentum. Cras et lacus sodales nisl facilisis ornare. Sed dolor eros, pulvinar ac varius non, bibendum eget odio. Nulla facilisi. Pellentesque et nisi a tellus ullamcorper faucibus. Nullam sagittis tempor mi non mattis. Proin ultricies, enim sit amet bibendum tristique, ligula ante feugiat nunc, sit amet imperdiet tortor nisl et felis. Pellentesque et nisl dui, non dictum libero. Vivamus tempor ante ac leo suscipit a sodales ligula iaculis. Curabitur massa mi, semper sed bibendum eget, auctor in nulla. Quisque at mi in ligula viverra suscipit sed vitae leo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>Thu Jan 19 00:00:00 -0600 2012</published>
				<link>http://bymichaellancaster.com//blog/why-I-choose-Jekyll-instead-wordpress</link>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
